University of Arizona Southwest Folklore Center records, 1979-[ongoing]
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Southwest Folklore Center records, 1979-[ongoing]
SWF 015
University of Arizona. Southwest Folklore Center.
21 linear feet
The collection consists of the administrative records, financial records and correspondence of the Southwest Folklore Center and its coordinator, James S. Griffith.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Southwest Folklore Center was founded in 1979 upon the dissolution of the University of Arizona Folklore Committee. Since then it has served as an archive for folklore material. Its activities include actively researching and collecting information about Arizona's folk communities, generating outreach programs, and coordinating folk activities throughout the state.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
I. Administrative Records, 1979-
II. Folklore Agencies Printed Materials, 1979-
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the administrative records, financial records and correspondence of the Southwest Folklore Center and its coordinator, James S. Griffith. The collection also includes some administrative files of the University of Arizona Folklore Committee, the Southwest Folklore Center's predecessor body. Records include correspondence with other folklore agencies in Arizona and other states, as well as correspondence with foundations, endowments and other grant-funding agencies. Information acquired by Griffith concerning other folklore and folklife agencies and programs throughout the United States and Mexico are also included in the collection.
Access Terms
University of Arizona. Southwest Folklore Center
Folklore archives -- Arizona -- Tucson
Folklore -- Arizona
Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1979-
  Administrative records, financial records and correspondence of the Southwest Folklore Center and its coordinator, James S. Griffith. This series also includes some administrative files of the University of Arizona Folklore Committee, the Southwest Folklore Center's predecessor body. Records include correspondence with other folklore agencies in Arizona and other states, as well as correspondence with foundations, endowments and other grant-funding agencies.
  - Administrative records. 1979-1987 (Box 1)
  - Office files, A - G. 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - General files, A - Z. 1980s (Box 3)
  - Office files, P - Z. 1980-1989 (Box 4)
  - General files; accounts; NEA. 1980s-1990s (Box 5)
  - Accounts, NEA grant, 1979-; Sunset Review, 1988; Library policy, 1993- 1979- (Box 6)
  - Job descriptions; finanical records. 1990s (Box 7)
  - Director's files. pre-1983 (Box 8)
  - Director's files. 1983-1987 (Box 9)
  - Director's notes. 1979-1996 (Box 10)
  - Director's notes. 1983-1996 (Box 11)
  - Director's correspondence. 1985-1996 (Box 12)
  - Publicity materials. 1979-1992 (Box 13)
- Series II: Folklore Agencies Printed Materials, 1979-
  Information acquired by James S. Griffith concerning other folklore and folklife agencies throughout the United States and Mexico.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by state.
  - A - C. (Box 14)
  - D - L. (Box 15)
  - M - N. (Box 16)
  - O - U. (Box 17)
  - V - W and Mexico. (Box 18)
  - Washington, DC (national agencies). (Box 19)